Guide to the Robin Kelley Hammer and Hoe Oral History Collection OH.040
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Robin Kelley Hammer and Hoe Oral History Collection
1986-1989
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Kelley, Robin D. G.
OH.040
1 Linear Feet in 1 shared cassette box and one compact disk box.
The collection's interviews were conducted by Robin Kelley as research for his book Hammer and Hoe: Alabama Communists During the Great Depression. The book, which was published by the University of North Carolina Press in 1990, documents the activities of the Alabama Communist Party in the 1930s and the impact of race and other cultural identities on the movement. The collection contains twelve oral history interviews taken by Kelley and one recorded radio program.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Robin Kelley in 1997. The accession number associated with this gift is 1997.077.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged chronologically.
Historical/Biographical Note
The collection's interviews were conducted by Robin Kelley as research for his book Hammer and Hoe: Alabama Communists During the Great Depression. The book, which was published by the University of North Carolina Press in 1990, documents the activities of the Alabama Communist Party in the 1930s and the impact of race and other cultural identities on the movement.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains twelve oral history interviews taken by Kelley and one recorded radio program. The collection documents the experiences of individuals involved with the Alabama Communist Party during the Great Depression.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Race discrimination -- United States.; Depressions |y 1929 |x Alabama; Communism |z Alabama; Communists |z Alabama |x History |y 20th Century; Jackson, Esther Cooper; Hudson, Hosea; Jackson, James E., 1914-2007; Communist Party of the United States of America
- James Jackson, Sep 26, 1986 (Box Shared Cassette Box 8, Cassette 1, Box 1, Cd 1)
- Hosea Hudson, Nov 15-16, 1986 (Box Shared Cassette Box 8, Cassette 2A-F, Box 1, Cd 2-7)
- H. D. Coke, Nov 25, 1986 (Box 1, Cd 8-9, Box Shared Cassette Box 8, Cassette 4A-B)
- Marge Frantz, Feb 6, 1987 (Box 1, Cd 10-11, Box Shared Cassette Box 8, Cassette 5A-B)
- Laurent Frantz, Feb 7, 1987 (Box 1, Cd 12-13, Box Shared Cassette Box 8, Cassette 5A-B)
- Rob Hall, Sep 18-19, 1987 (Box 1, Cd 14-15, Box Shared Cassette Box 8, Cassette 6A-B)
- Dr. Kelley on Dr. King, WNBH - New Bedford, Jan 14, 1988 (Box Shared Cassette Box 8, Cd 16, Drawer 40, Cassette 7)
- Esther Cooper Jackson, Jun 22, 1988 (Box 1, Cd 17, Box Shared Cassette Box 8, Cassette 8)
- Alice Burke (Jarvis), Oct 14, 1988 (Box 1, Cd 18, Box Shared Cassette Box 8, Cassette 9)
- Nannie Washburn, Dec 21, 1989 (Box 1, Cd 19, Box Shared Cassette Box 8, Cassette 10)
- Charles Echols and Mack Robinson, undated (Box 1, Cd 20, Box Shared Cassette Box 8, Cassette 11)